## DANIEL JAMES FOLEY

Address: 72 Festival Crescent, Pontypool, New inn, NP4 0NH
Contact: 07803 326264 | Email: djf1991@hotmail.co.uk

### **Profile**

Computer Science student at University of the West of England. A determined, self-motivated and passionate individual with a record of achieving high quality and reliable results. Keen to continuously develop technical and interpersonal skills to deliver consistently high results. A good communicator who is comfortable working individually or as part of a team with experience of leading a group of individuals, to motivate and drive them to achieve a common goal.

## **Key Skills**

C, Java, (Advanced) HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL (Advanced) VBA (Advanced) C++, C#, python (Novice) x86 Assembler, bash script (Novice) ABAP (Novice)

MS Office (Advanced) SharePoint (Intermediate) Data Modelling (UML/JSD)

Netbeans / Visual Studio Spring MVC Waterfall / Agile / Scrum Methodology

ITIL Service Management Incident Management Problem Management

Change Management Solution Manager SAP (Basic)

Problem Solving Teamwork Communication (Verbal / Written)

Project Management QwikSolver (Lean Six Sigma principles) ERP

#### **Education**

BSc Computer Science University of the West of England (Predicted First Class Honours)

Foundation Year for Computing: Overall 82(%) (First)

2010 - Present
2010 - 2011

Computer Architecture (70%), Programming design & implementation (80%), Programming project (94%).

Year 1: Overall: 79% (First)

Introduction to Program Development (91%), Analytical modelling (87%), Computer systems architecture (66%), Computer Science Concepts (66%), Introduction to AI (85%).

Year 2: Overall: 78% (First) 2012 - 2013

Computer networks & operating systems (78%), Data structures and algorithms (77%), Data, Schemas & Applications (76%), Symbolic AI (87%), Sub-Symbolic AI (70%).

Year 3: To date: 85% (Predicted First) 2014 – 2015

Final year project: Customisable issue tracking system in line with ITIL best practices

GCSE / A-Levels: 12 GCSEs A-C (Inc. English, Maths and Science) & 2 A-Levels (IT)

# **Work Experience**

## **Xerox Corporation London, UK**

# SAP Solution Manager 7.1 ITSM & ChaRM Transition Analyst (3 months)

**July 2014 – September 2014** 

2011 - 2012

- Required to analyse and understand the new change and release management (ChaRM) process being introduced within SAP Solution Manager 7.1
- To understand the multiple change and release processes related to ESAP and our Legacy SAP systems across Europe, to assist the development of one single unified process and the creation of process documentation
- Responsible for creating documentation related to ChaRM and Quality Gate project creation
- · Identity process gaps, areas susceptible to risk and to suggest controls to mitigate future issues
- Assist with the development and execution of test scenarios and test scripts related to IT service management (ITSM)
  incident and problem management.

## **Xerox Corporation London, UK**

#### Information Management / Service Delivery Support Analyst (12 months placement)

June 2013 - July 2014

- Leading two SAP support and functional pack upgrades. I was given this responsibility to assist the team during a period of increased workload. It was a challenging yet rewarding opportunity giving me valuable project management experience. Key tasks included:
  - Ensuring all Stakeholders understood the upgrade timelines and committed resources to support the activity
  - Coordinating with our 3rd party support provider based offshore to ensure project tasks were completed as planned.
  - Communicating and coordinating activities with key business users during UAT. Ensuring test scripts are documented and evidenced
  - Monitoring testing and defects during UAT and communicating with all stakeholders to ensure fixes are completed and testing within the required timescales.
  - o Ensuring all stakeholder approvals for project go-live are in line with audit requirements
  - Escalating any risks and issues to line manager
- Document analysis and key management reporting
- Responsible for managing the supplier billing process in the team. Collecting management approvals, validating Purchase Orders and invoices and processing payment approvals
- Monitoring system performance and maintaining key documents identifying critical system issues.
- I automated existing processes and daily tasks reducing errors and improving efficiency
- Communicating with business users across Europe and coordinating resolution of incidents with 3<sup>rd</sup> party support providers based onshore and offshore.
- Supporting other IT departments to maintain work rate through holiday periods
- Analyse ticketing tool data to produce new innovative reports for ticket trending and strategy analysis
- Managing, monitoring and reporting security and authorisation issues
- Maintaining application approval matrix, key processes in line with Sarbanes Oxley requirements
- Participating in monthly technical review meetings reviewing service delivery metrics and application technical performance in line with ITIL principles.
- Developing and updating internal web sites to ensure that key information is available to Xerox employees and 3rd party application support providers across Europe.

#### **Asda Walmart**

## **Customer Assistant (1 year 9 months)**

Sep 2011 – June 2013

- For financial support during university I worked at Asda where my key responsibilities were stock control and stock replenishment.
- Other roles included: checkout operator and the warehouse management team.
- Working closely with team leads, trading managers and store managers to make processes efficient and to organise work force more effectively.
- Supporting the team across departments during busy periods to drive towards common goal.
- Further developed my ability to adapt to different working environments and engage with customers of differing personalities and attitudes.

## Tesco

## **Customer Assistant (4 years 6 months)**

June 11 - Sep 11 & June 08 - Sep 10

- From self-evaluation, I identified that I had weak communication skills, lacking the ability to talk to new individuals.
- Continuous exposure to new individuals I built on this weakness,
- Dedication and motivation were key skills to the success of this objective.
- During my time, I practiced time management, analytical thinking and interpersonal skills from my roles in warehouse management, checkout operator and shop floor assistant.

## Interests and activities

- Developing websites and custom content management systems for small businesses.
- Keep fit and active by regularly playing 5-a-side football and attending a local gym.
- Organising and participating in charity events for various charity organisations

## **Other Information**

- Awarded the 'Deans award for Academic Excellence' at University for achieving consistently high results.
- Presented project work and experiences to the Xerox CIO during my time as an industrial placement student
- Holder of a Full Clean UK driving licence

## References